welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it topic 4.4 is about America's
relations with other countries
throughout the beginning of the 19th
century so it's fair to say America was
struggling in this time to create a
global presence turns out inciting a
revolution to create a nation doesn't
get respect from other nations that have
been on the globe for much longer the US
tried to rectify this through things
like the War of 1812 but they needed
more land what they did first was
acquire Florida from Spain in 1819 under
these two treaties and they also started
a war where they forced the seminal
tribes out of the for B lands the US
also decided to prove their Naval might
which they did by inciting the Barbary
Wars against North African States but
the big thing to talk about is as
America kept spreading Westward there
was more and more conflict with Native
Americans Britain saw this as an
opportunity to support the Native
Americans against the Americans this
would cause President James Monroe to
pass the Monroe Doctrine which declared
to Britain that any involvement in
America by European powers would be seen
as an act of war and to add insult to
injury America also passed mayon's bill
number two which prohibited French and
British warship from entering American
Harbors on the screen now or AP style
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now please follow my social medias and
I'll see you in the next one